Guide to the People's Mutual Benevolent Association of NC, Iredell Division records, 1902-1907
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
People's Mutual Benevolent Association of NC, Iredell Division papers 1902-1907
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
People's Mutual Benevolent Association.
0.5 linear feet Extent: 44 Items
The People's Mutual Benevolent Association of NC, incorporated 1897 February 20, was a life insurance company with headquarters in Raleigh, N.C. The records of the People's Mutual Benevolent Association of NC, Iredell Division consist of financial files, a small amount of correspondence concerning various matters, and other business papers. They are arranged in rough chronological order. Some of the records may provide information about a 1906 NC Supreme Court Case action of Helen Hay against People's Mutual concerning unpaid dues and reinstatement.
peoplesmutual
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The People's Mutual Benevolent Association of NC, Iredell Division records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1948.
Collection Overview
The records of the People's Mutual Benevolent Association of NC, Iredell Division consist of financial files, a small amount of correspondence concerning various matters, and other business papers. They are arranged in rough chronological order. Some of the records may provide information about a 1906 NC Supreme Court Case action of Helen Hay against People's Mutual concerning unpaid dues and reinstatement.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
People's Mutual Benevolent Association of North Carolina (Raleigh, N.C.); Life insurance -- North Carolina; Business records -- North Carolina; Iredell County (N.C.)--History
Contents of Collection
- People's Mutual Benevolent Association of NC, Iredell Division records, 1902-1907, (1 box)
  Arrangement is roughly chronological.
  - Application, 1903 June 13 (Box 1)
  - Letters from Secretary Treasurers regarding payments and other financial matters (Box 1)
  - Letters to Secretary Treasurers regarding policies stricken from the books (Box 1)
  - Letter from Secretary Treasurer J. Whiteware regarding insurance fraud, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Deaths, Assessments and Reserve Fund sheets (Box 1)
  - Annual dues, 1904-1907 (Box 1)
  - 26th Assessment, 1907 Apr. 17 (Box 1)
  - Bank checks, circa 1905 (Box 1)
  - Teacher's attendance book used as policy record (Box 1)